血压  赶紧恢复血压啊
Pressure. I need pressure.
凯莉钳穿上缝线给我  我需要肾上腺素
Get me sutures on a Kelly. Need an EPI.
安排手术室  准备10单位血  通知创伤科
Get OR. Ten unpacked. Alert trauma.
我们得记录下这是一场正式听证会
Let the record show that we are officially convening
有关于2012年2月3日209病房里
a disciplinary hearing regarding the events
所发生的事
of February 3, 2012 in patient room 209.
豪斯医生  这份记录将会
Dr. House, this recording will be transcribed
同其它文件和判决材料
and published along with
一起转录及公布
all supporting documentation and rulings.
在开始前  你还有什么疑问吗
Do you have any questions before we get started?
有
Yeah.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是沃尔特·科菲尔德  仁爱医院的
I'm Walter Cofield, Chief of Neurology,
神经内科主任
Mercy Hospital.
今天  你的命运我说了算
I'll be deciding your fate today.
科菲尔德
Cofield.
在你去仁爱医院之前
You were the Residency Director at Hopkins
是霍普金斯医院的原住院医生主管
before you moved to Mercy,
也就是说
which means it's safe to assume
福曼是你一手培养的
that you trained Foreman,
也就意味着他很相信你
which means it's also safe to assume that he trusts you.
这次听证会的对象不是我  豪斯医生
This hearing isn't about me, Dr. House.
我知道你想把矛头指向我
I know you'd like to make it about me,
好让你为自己开脱
because then it wouldn't be about you.
他选自己过去的恩师
It's interesting
来审现在的恩师  真有意思
that he'd pick the old mentor to judge the new one.
是挺有意思  但无关紧要
Interesting, but not relevant.
另一方面  这个病例的真实情况...
The facts of this case, on the other hand--
真实情况都在病历里写着呢
The facts are in the file.
总监：
zlean
如果你看不懂我的字
If you have trouble reading my handwriting,
医学顾问：
徐
给我打电话
give me a call.
我要回去工作了
I'm going back to work.
如果我只参考病历做决断的话
If I just consider the file,
你可占不到什么便宜
the facts aren't in your favor.
有事实证明你应该被停职
The facts say you should be suspended,
按我的理解
which, from what I understand,
这样的话  你的假释也就得终止了
would mean a revocation of your parole.
病人是个32岁的高中化学老师
The patient was a 32-year-old high school chemistry teacher.
他在慢跑时昏倒
He collapsed while out jogging.
他四肢瘫痪
He was paralyzed in all four extremities
然而扫描结果...
despite the fact that the scans...
显示没有中风或者其它结构性病变的迹象
Show no sign of stroke or structural lesions.
那赶紧去通缉一辆
Put out an APB for a car
保险杠上有人形凹槽的汽车吧
with a man-shaped dent in the grill.
没有骨折  没有创伤
No broken bones, no signs of trauma.
横贯性脊髓炎
Transverse myelitis.
真无聊
Boring.
核磁共振没有增强
No enhancement on the MRI.
我不知道下一步该怎么办了
I just don't know what to do.
求你了  你得帮我搞定这个病人
Please, you have to help me solve this thing.
我就加了点诗意嘛
A little poetic license.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
吃我的维柯...他命
Taking my vic-amins.
那是维柯丁吗
Those are Vicodin?
你最近动过手术吗
Did you have surgery recently?
大概十年前吧
About a decade ago.
我的腿疼可算不来时间
My leg is no good at judging time.
你在处理这个病例期间有没有服用维柯丁
Were you taking Vicodin during this case?
有
Yes.
在处理过去九年间的所有病例时都这样
And during about nine years of previous cases.
我这么做是经过许可的
My process is proven.
好事常有
Good things usually happen.
坏事不常有
Bad things sometimes happen.
当出了状况时
And when bad things happen,
我们就得搞明白是哪块出了问题
we should figure out what went wrong,
这样我们才能吸取教训改正错误
so we can learn from it and correct it.
是这样我们就能横加指责
So that we can assign blame
而不是意识到
instead of recognizing
有时就是会出状况
that bad things sometimes happen.
弄成这样谁都没错
It was nobody's fault.
之后怎么了
And then what happened?
有能力的人就去营生
Those who can, do.
没能力的人就去教书
Those who can't, teach.
不会教书的  教体育
Those who can't teach, teach gym.
不会教体育的
Those who can't move their arms or legs
便要教我们嘲笑他人
teach us to laugh at others.
豪斯真的是这么陈述病人情况的吗
House actually presented the case in that way,
还是你故意让他难堪
or are you just trying to make him look bad?
我为什么要故意让他难堪
Why would I be trying to make him look bad?
可能是你并不很隐晦地想暗示
Could be your not-so-subtle way of implying
这是豪斯的错
this was House's fault.
鉴于发生的事实
Given what's happened, it's understandable
你在你的证词里带有感情色彩是很正常的
that your opinion would color your testimony,
但我只想知道你当时说了什么
but I just want to know what you said, what you did,
做了什么  是怎么想的
and what you were thinking at the time.
我认为不是他的错
I don't think it was his fault.
告诉我你最初的判断
Just tell me your initial theory.
我一开始认为病人是肝有问题
I thought the patient had a liver problem.
肝性脑病可以解释他昏过去
Hepatic encephalopathy explained why he passed out,
以及四肢瘫痪的原因
why he couldn't move his limbs.
但豪斯不同意你的观点
But that's not the idea House went with.
他认为陶博的想法很蠢
He thought Taub's idea was stupid.
那你是怎么想的
And what about your idea?
他认为我的想法也很蠢
He thought that was stupid too.
不  我是问  你的想法是什么
No, I meant, what was it?
我认为病人是正常压力性脑积水
Oh. I thought the patient had normal pressure hydrocephalus.
那为什么豪斯认为这是个蠢主意
And why did House think that was stupid?
得了吧
Oh, come on.
除非你也是个蠢蛋
Unless you're an idiot,
不然你肯定知道我为什么认为朴克是蠢货
you know why I thought Park was an idiot.
患者腰椎穿刺术中起始脑脊液压力低
The patient had low opening pressure on his LP.
我就是这么说的
That's what I said.
不对  你这个笨蛋
No, you idiot.
患者腰椎穿刺术中起始脑脊液压力低
The patient had low opening pressure on his LP.
下次睁大你们的眼睛仔细看看检查结果好不好
Try unsquinting your eyes and reading the labs next time.
你是在故意惹我生气
Are you intentionally trying to get me
想让我讨厌你吗
to dislike you?
那不是我  是椅子说的
That wasn't me. The chair squeaked.
你明知这是在录证词  还要用
You're testifying, for the record,
"睁大你们的眼睛"这句话吗
that you actually used the phrasing "Unsquint your eyes"?
这可不是你展露内疚的地方
It's not the place to exercise your guilt.
我真的说了这句话
I actually used the phrasing
"睁大你们的眼睛"
"Unsquint your eyes".
他的血钾过低
He's hypokalemic.
可能意味着心脏有问题
Could indicate a problem with his heart,
-这可能是...  -心电图正常
- which would-- - EKG was normal.
但奇斯  真正仔细看
But Chase, a doctor who actually takes the time
检查结果的医生说的有道理
to read the lab reports, has a point.
这家伙的钾太低了
The guy's potassium is off.
可能是甲亢性瘫痪  给他用...
Could be thyrotoxic paralysis. Start him on...
类固醇  丙基硫氧嘧啶  β受体阻滞剂
Steroids, PTU, and beta blockers.
这些橙色的印记是怎么弄到病历上的
And how did these orange smudges get on the patient files?
你真的假的
Seriously?
你接下来就准备问这问题吗
That's your follow-up?
我吃了好多奇多  而且忘了洗手
I eat a lot of cheetos. I forget to wash my hands.
我吃的零食跟这病例有关吗
Is my snacking really relevant to this case?
如果这些真是奇多圈的印记的话  有可能
Might be, if these were actually cheetos' stains.
到底是什么
What are they?
真的假的  豪斯
Seriously, House?
你还能怪我啊
You're blaming me?
你用的是亚当斯的洗发水
You used Adams' shampoo.
不是我干的
I didn't do it.
那只是个无伤大雅的小恶作剧
It was a harmless prank.
我的团队成员都很有个性
My team is made up of Type-A personalities.
他们偶尔都需要放松一下
They need something to break the tension
以缓解他们的压力
every once in a while.
也就是说这是一个增进团队凝聚力的活动吗
So this was a team-building exercise?
他是这么说的吗
Is that what he called it?
他是这么暗示的
That's what he implied.
豪斯更喜欢混乱  而不是团结
House prefers chaos over cohesion.
他坚信同事间意见相左
He believes that disagreement and mistrust
互不信任会激发出好点子
lead to better ideas.
他说的没错
He's not wrong.
你是说他说的对吗
As opposed to being right?
那么你们就给病人用了类固醇
So you treated with steroids.
-之后怎么样了  -起效果了
- And then what happened? - They worked.
我们的病人醒了
Our patient woke up.
比尔
Bill?
你能听见我吗
Can you hear me?
能
Yeah.
我好渴
I'm thirsty.
这很正常
That's normal.
你已经昏迷了几个小时了
You've been in a coma for several hours.
能告诉我你的名字吗
Can you tell me your name?
比尔
Uh, Bill.
比尔·科普曼
Bill Koppelman.
能告诉我发生了什么吗
Can you tell me what happened to me?
我们正在治疗你的甲状腺亢进
We're treating you for an overactive thyroid.
我们认为这是你昏倒和不能动的病因
We think that's why you passed out and couldn't move.
你能动下手指吗
Can you wiggle your fingers for me?
他会好起来吗
Is he going to be okay?
不好意思  只有家庭成员才可以进来
Excuse me, but only family members are allowed.
没关系
It's okay.
他们是我的学生
They're my students.
学校里的每个人都非常担心你
Everyone back at school is so worried about you.
他生病是因为那次爆炸吗
Is he sick because of the explosion?
-什么爆炸  -什么爆炸
- What explosion? - What explosion?
什么爆炸
What explosion?
他在班上做的化学实验
A chemistry demonstration he was doing
出了问题
for his class went wrong.
为什么这点没记录在病史上
Why was it not already in the patient history?
因为当时病人失去意识了
Because the patient was unconscious.
但我以为豪斯医生同病人妻子聊过了
But I'm assuming Dr. House spoke to the wife.
妻子并不知道那次爆炸
The wife didn't know about the explosion.
并且是我对她进行的询问
And I was the one who questioned her,
因此如果这算是疏忽的话
so, if there was an oversight,
那责任在我
it was mine.
难道豪斯医生认为病人的病史不重要吗
Does Dr. House not attach importance to patient histories?
不  他认为病史至关重要
No, he thinks they're crucial.
只是和病人共处一间屋子里
He just doesn't think being in the same room
并不重要
as the patient is crucial.
豪斯认为避免和病人接触
House thinks avoiding patients
可以使他尽可能保持客观的判断
allows him to stay as objective as possible.
他没错
He's not wrong.
听上去像是为他的懒惰找了个冠冕堂皇的借口
Sounds like a very diplomatic way of saying he's lazy.
那也没错
That's also true.
无论怎样  有人替我干
Either way, I'm covered.
如果你想得到准确的病史
If you want an accurate patient history,
不要询问病人本人
don't ever talk to the patient.
人人都会撒谎
Everybody lies.
除我以外
Except me.
对你
To you.
我绝不会在这里撒谎
Would never do that.
好吧  就算你是对的
Okay. Say you're right.
如果是你在屋子里
If you had actually been in the room,
询问那个病人
questioning the patient,
你就能看到他的肢体语言
you could read body language,
问些后续问题
you could ask follow-up questions,
警告他欺骗你的后果
warn him of the costs of lying to you.
别忘了还能严刑逼供
Don't forget the thumbscrews.
你能否承认
Can you dispute the possibility that,
如果你更早的接触到病人
had you visited the patient sooner,
也许同他的妻子
maybe talked to the wife,
或是他的学生聊聊
been directed to one of the students,
这个病例的结果可能会大不相同吗
that this case might have ended very differently?
那并不能完全算是一次爆炸
It wasn't exactly an explosion.
那是一次可控反应
It was a controlled reaction
只是有点失控
that went a little haywire.
那就是一次爆炸
It was too an explosion.
西蒙·哈里斯用他的手机拍下了全过程
Simon Harris filmed the whole thing on his camera phone
并且放到了Youtube上
and posted it on YouTube.
已经有七万五千次的点击率了
It got, like, over 75,000 hits already.
听上去你出名了亲爱的
Looks like you've gone viral, Hon.
他失去知觉
He had a loss of consciousness,
暂时性麻痹...
temporary paralysis...
但当我被告知病人开始咳血时
But when I was told the patient coughed up blood,
事情开始变得有意思了
then things really started to get interesting.
你的病人不但要忍受双倍的疼痛并且伴有咳血
Your patient was doubled over in pain and coughing up blood,
你居然觉得有趣吗
and you found that interesting?
怎么  难道不好吗
Why, is that bad?
确实有趣
It's interesting.
我每年都做这个实验
I do this demonstration every year.
一般都是助教帮我准备器材
I usually have a student aide help me set it up,
很明显今年他加了过多的氢氟酸
and apparently this year he added extra hydrofluoric acid,
这正是发生爆炸的原因
which is why it exploded.
那个助教只是想录个高点击率的视频
The student aide was just trying to make a viral video,
没想伤害任何人
not hurt anyone.
结果事与愿违
Ended up doing both.
因此我们认为病人吸入了大剂量的
So we figured the patient inhaled the extra large dose
氢氟酸导致
of hydrofluoric acid and...
肺部灼伤
Burned his lungs,
因此他才会咳血
which is why he coughed up blood.
就好像烧坏肺叶能解释
If only burnt lungs explained
晕倒和麻痹一样
the passing out and paralysis.
爆炸能  重新看一遍视频
The explosion does. Check out the video again.
他的头撞到了墙
He smacked his head against the wall.
如果那导致了脑干肿胀
If that caused swelling in his brainstem,
最终会引起知觉丧失
that would have led to eventual loss
以及身体麻痹
of consciousness and paralysis.
我们讨论了一会
So we discussed it a little longer,
然后豪斯决定用肝素进行治疗
and House decided to treat with Heparin.
我不介意你说的更详细些
I wouldn't mind a couple more details.
是肝素气雾剂
It was aerosolized Heparin.
你跳过了鉴别诊断的过程
You skipped over the actual DDX,
而现在你移开了你的目光
and now you're averting your eyes.
我对当时的情况越来越好奇了
I'm growing more and more curious by the moment.
他的头撞到了墙
He smacked his head against the wall.
如果那导致了脑干肿胀
If that caused swelling in his brainstem,
最终会引起知觉丧失
that would have led to eventual loss
以及身体麻痹
of consciousness and paralysis.
所有人不许动
Nobody move.
他  他戴了什么
He--he had on a what?
防毒面具
Gas mask.
那个臭弹是奇斯做的
The stink bomb was Chase's.
他是想为橘色头发的事进行报复
He was getting revenge for the orange hair
因此把它藏在了豪斯的办公室里
and rigged it in House's office.
但豪斯发现了
But House found it.
我有答案了你们才能走
You can leave when I have an answer.
如果我们知道问题的话
It might help if we knew the question.
如何治疗
How do we treat
肺叶里的化学灼伤
chemical burns inside the lungs?
也许可以用水进行
Maybe we can use a bronchoalveolar lavage
支气管肺泡灌洗
to wash 'em out with water.
不好意思  我的错  我该说清楚的
Sorry. My fault. Should have clarified.
如何才能治疗肺叶内的
How do we treat chemical burns
化学灼伤而不杀死病人
inside the lungs without killing the patient?
磺胺嘧啶银盐治疗化学灼伤很有效
Silver sulfadiazine works well on chemical burns.
灼伤类乳液会导致他更快的被溺死
Burn cream would drown him faster than water.
还有吗
Well?
肝素气雾剂
Aerosolized Heparin.
我喜欢
Me likey.
但那还在试验阶段
But that's only experimental.
从没进行过临床应用
It's never actually been used before.
不完全是
Not true.
已经在羊身上用过了
Been used in sheep.
病人情况恶化很快
The guy was going downhill fast.
我们需要进行某种治疗以...
We needed a treatment that was a...
改变这种情况
slope changer.
因此你就打碎了那个二氧化硫的臭弹
So you busted out the sulfur dioxide stink bomb?
相当于一次团队建设训练
It was a team-building exercise.
不  你这是操纵
No. It was manipulation.
你迫使你的团队为了离开那间屋子而
You were pressuring your team into coming up
想出一个不安全的治疗方案
with unsafe medical ideas just to get out of that room.
你说是压力  我觉得是启发
You say pressure, I say inspire.
常规安全的方法不会起作用的
The usual safe ideas were not gonna work.
肝素气雾剂可能有用
Aerosolized Heparin might.
其他人就这么同意了吗
And everyone else just went along with this?
不
No.
我告诉豪斯我认为那是个错误
I told House I thought it was a mistake.
那是你当时的原话吗
And those were your exact words?
我想我的原话是他疯了
I think I might have said insane.
你认为他疯了但还是任他为所欲为
You thought it was insane, and yet you let it happen.
-不  我...- 如果你在病人安全方面
- No, I-- - If you disagree
不同意豪斯医生的意见   医生
with Dr. House on patient safety, Doctor,
你的职责就是说出来
it is your duty to speak up.
否则你也同样应受到谴责
Otherwise, you are equally to blame.
我确实说了  我努力了
I did speak up. I tried.
但你失败了
And you failed.
因此我去找了福曼医生
And that's why I went to Dr. Foreman.
肝素可能会导致血液
The Heparin could cause the patient to bleed
更快的流入病人肺中
into his lungs even faster.
这方案是很疯狂
It is crazy,
但豪斯不是为了发疯而发疯
but House doesn't do crazy just for crazy's sake.
如果他认为这是唯一能帮助病人的方法...
If he thinks this is the only way to help your patient...
当你让我调查这个病例时
You did not tell me you were involved in this case
你没告诉我你也参与其中
when you asked me to do this.
我没有
I wasn't.
对于肝素的决定
The Heparin decision
对结果没有任何影响
didn't have anything to do with the outcome.
若豪斯的决定你都给予通行
If signing off on everything House does is a pattern,
就会影响到豪斯的行为
it affects the way House behaves,
进而影响到豪斯的团队
it affects the way House's team reacts
如何回应他的行为
to the way House behaves.
豪斯...
House...
是天才
is brilliant.
多数时候  我都不会反对他的决定
I give him the benefit of the doubt most of the time
因为我见识过他的能力
because I've seen what he can do.
让豪斯出狱 是你当院长以来
Getting House out of prison is the biggest decision
做出的最大的决定  不是吗
you've made as Dean of Medicine, right?
如果他在此次听证后被停职
And if he's suspended as a result of this hearing,
就违反了假释条例  得重回监狱
he violates his parole and he goes back.
估计这会让院长的头衔成为你的过去
And that probably leaves you as former Dean of Medicine.
应该是的
I suppose so.
你让我来监督这事并非因为
You didn't choose me to oversee this
你认为我能保持客观
because you thought I could be objective.
你选中我是因为  你以为我会保你万全
You chose me because you thought I'd have your back
对于会导致你被炒鱿鱼的决定
and I'd think twice about making a decision
我会慎重考虑
that would get you fired.
艾瑞克
Eric.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
但若你这放虎归山的险招
But if your get-House-out-of-jail-free
是搬起石头砸自己的脚
experiment blows up in your face,
帮你渡过难关可不是我的责任
it's not my job to get you out of it.
在你决定使用肝素后
After you'd administered the Heparin,
我发现病历中有张出院许可
I see there was a discharge order on the chart,
但病人从未出院
and yet the patient never left.
豪斯让病人先做治疗式沐浴
House ordered a therapeutic bath first
以洗去爆炸后残留的化学物质
to wash off any residual chemicals from the blast.
但我们另有发现
But we wound up finding something.
你发了点皮疹
You have a bit of a rash.
能把两臂抬高吗
Can you raise both your arms?
让我检查下面积有多大
I just need to see how far it goes.
你跟我说我会好转的
You told me I was going to be okay.
但我的身体还是有问题
And now there's still something wrong with me.
这可能不是大问题
It probably doesn't mean anything,
我们只是确认一下
but we want to make sure.
就知道你这么说
Of course you do.
我要离开这里
I got to get out of here, okay?
-放轻松  -让我离开这
- Just relax. - Please just let me get out of here.
很快就好
It'll just take a minute.
我们只是要看一下皮疹
We just need to get a good look at the rash.
皮疹吗  那个不是问题
The rash? That was nothing.
只是因为躺了一天捂得
Just some irritation from lying in bed all day.
问题在于病人的精神状态
The problem was the patient's brain.
他吓坏了
He freaked out.
我要走
I got to--I got to get out.
我一定要走
I got to get out of here.
说"吓坏了"有点夸张
"Freak out" is a little strong.
当时我的观点是
In my opinion at the time,
皮疹才是会致死的病因
it was the rash that was gonna kill him.
链状球菌感染
Invasive strep.
有证据支持的合理诊断
Reasonable theory, supported by the evidence.
症状表明是精神错乱
The evidence pointed to psychosis.
因为我们在他初入院时
We caused it by giving him steroids
给他用了类固醇
when he first came in.
你的观点呢
What'd you think?
我认为朴克和亚当斯的观察都对
I thought Park and Adams were both right
但她俩的结论都错了
but that their conclusions were both wrong.
神经症状和皮疹都是
The neuro symptoms and the rash were both signs
病人所患病的症状
of an underlying disease.
再加上肺部问题  结合起来是韦格纳病
Together with the lung, it added up to Wegener's.
三个能干的医生
How does Dr. House handle it
得出三个不同但皆有理的诊断
when three smart doctors come up with
这时豪斯医生要怎么办
three different but equally valid ideas?
我会进行诊断性试验
I run a diagnostic trial.
给病人使用高剂量类固醇
Start the patient on high-dose steroids.
一石多鸟
Multiple birds, single stone.
若陶博是对的  他就能立刻病愈出院
If Taub is right, then he will walk out of here cured.
若亚当斯是对的  他会发烧
If Adams is right, he'll spike a fever,
出现低血压  我们再对症下药
get hypotensive, we can treat it.
他便能病愈出院
He can walk out of here cured.
若朴克是对的
If Park is right,
他就会大发神经
he goes all Cuckoo's Nest on us,
能确认病因在于大脑
we can cross "brain" off the list,
做出诊断  他也能病愈出院
diagnose him, and he can walk out of here cured.
你是让我更快做决定吗
Are you trying to make this easy for me?
你自己承认
By your own admission,
若给病人用类固醇
if you give the patient steroids,
会有三分之二的几率变得更严重
two of the three outcomes are gonna make him worse.
若不能给出诊断
What was making the patient worse
才会让病情更严重
was not having a diagnosis.
这是得出结论的最快方式
This was the fastest way to get it.
这算是完美的诊断学时刻
It was a perfect diagnostic moment.
考虑到发生的事情
In light of what happened,
你还认为这是完美的诊断学时刻吗
you still think it was the perfect diagnostic moment?
是的
Yes.
我的理论考虑到了所有医学结果
My theory accounted for all the medical outcomes.
但没考虑到我的手下会不听话
It did not account for the disobedience of my own team.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我觉得关于链状球菌你说得对
I think you're right about the strep.
等待时做下活检也无伤大雅
Can't hurt to biopsy the rash while we're waiting.
谢谢
Thanks.
当时  这看起来是个好主意
At the time, it seemed like a good idea.
我知道这很难
I know this is hard,
但请你一五一十的告诉我接下来发生了什么
but please tell me exactly what happened next.
来点儿麻醉
Draw up a little anesthetic.
2毫升利多卡因
Two CCs Lidocaine.
离我远点
Get away from me.
你是在医院里  冷静下来
You're in a hospital. Calm down.
安全警报
Code Grey!
所以你认为原因在于你的团队
So your position is that your team's disobedience
-不守指令  -我没这么说
- caused this? - That's not what I said.
你说你没料到他们没按你说的做
You said you didn't anticipate their defiance.
就是在暗示  不然的话一切都没问题
You implied that all would have been fine otherwise.
那你说是谁的错
So who do you blame,
亚当斯医生  还是奇斯医生
Dr. Adams or Dr. Chase?
或两人都是
Or both?
两人个都不是
I don't blame either one.
那你说是谁呢  豪斯医生
So who do you blame, Dr. House?
安全警报
Code Grey!
拿氟哌啶醇[强效安定]
Get haloperidol.
我来
Got it.
我的天  奇斯
Oh, my God, Chase.
准备手术室  推个轮床过来
Prep the O.R. and get a gurney.
开始静脉注射
Start an I.V.
出血点一定在这儿
Come on. The bleeder's got to be in here.
-找到了  -哪条动脉
- Got it. - Which artery?
是他的心脏
It's his heart.
幸运的是  只是刀尖伤到了心肌
Fortunately, only the knife tip reached the cardiac muscle.
在左心室划了一道口子
Made a laceration in the left ventricle
大约有我食指尖那么大
about the size of the tip of my index finger.
那时  只有我手指堵上伤口
At that moment, he could only stay alive
他才能活下去
as long as my finger plugged the hole.
躺在地上的很可能是我
It could have been me on the floor.
本该是我
It should have been me.
那是我的诊断
It was my theory.
我在病人眼前晃针头
I held the needle in front of the patient
让他精神错乱起来
that set off his paranoia.
如果你在找是谁的错
If you're looking for someone to blame...
那就是我
blame me.
请继续
Please continue.
出现异位性搏动
Getting some ectopy.
-让一让  -颈动脉搏动很强
- Coming through. - Good carotid pulse.
正常吗
Regular?
-不  -出现室性期前收缩
- No. - Got a PVC.
大家让一让
Got to move it, people.
我的诊断试验有效果
My diagnostic test worked.
证明病人患有类固醇诱发性精神病
It proved the patient had a steroid-induced psychosis.
这就是你对这一情况的反映吗
And that's what you took away from this situation?
精神问题并非是症状之一
The brain was not a symptom of an underlying disease.
你的同事被捅伤了
Your colleague was stabbed.
你是说你不关心吗
Are you telling me you didn't care?
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
很糟
Bad.
给我补片
Patch.
-准备好了吗  -我不能移开手指
- Ready? - I can't take my finger out.
他会大出血  我觉得他挺不过去
He'll bleed. I don't think he can take it.
血氧量已饱和
Oxygenation's at 100%.
也只能听天由命了
He's as ready as he's gonna be.
我们得放手一搏
We got to go for it.
听我口令
On my count.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
缝合
Suture.
好了  血压稳定
Got it. BP is stable.
补片堵住了伤口
Patch is holding.
他的心跳是多少
What was his heart rate?
他没有心跳
He doesn't have one.
-他还在心脏分流  -不是奇斯的
- He's on bypass. - Not Chase.
病人的心跳
The patient.
你这是在鉴别诊断吗
You're DDX-ing?
朴克  跟我来
Park, come with me.
这儿有陶博负责
Taub's got this.
就是因为你不听我言
My friend is here
奇斯才会如此下场
because you didn't listen to me.
我有听你的  是奇斯没听我的
I did listen to you. Chase didn't listen to me.
事到如今
At this point,
你在这里只是图个心里安慰
being here makes you feel better.
你既帮不了奇斯也帮不了我们的病人
You're not helping Chase or our patient.
好吧
Fine.
他就这么离开了
So he just walked out?
确实没他什么事儿
There really was nothing for him to do.
你不觉得
Speaks to a certain callousness
豪斯医生很无情吗
on Dr. House's part, don't you think?
谁管他是不是冷酷无情
Who cares if House was callous?
你要为了这个惩罚他吗
Are you gonna punish callousness?
但你不认为同情心
But you agree that empathy
是身为医生非常重要的品质吗
is a useful quality for doctors?
这不是豪斯的问题
House is not the problem.
你的朋友被刺伤了
Your friend got stabbed.
生命垂危
He may die from those wounds.
如果你在那个房间里
If you had been in that room,
可能被刺伤的人就是你
maybe that could have been you.
我才不会进那个房间
I wouldn't have been in the room.
你是在暗示  奇斯他是咎由自取吗
Implicitly, you just said that Chase was at fault.
我们都知道精神失常
We all knew a psychotic episode
是三种可能的结果之一
was one of the three possible outcomes.
而奇斯带了把手术刀进房间
And Chase brought a scalpel in there.
他的举动威胁到了亚当斯医生
He endangered Dr. Adams,
那个病人  以及他自己
he endangered himself, and he endangered the patient.
谢谢
Thank you.
肺部问题  出皮疹
Lungs, rash,
加之现在的心率变异性增加
now excessive R-R variability.
快想
Go.
这是家医院
It's a hospital.
有的是医生
There are lots of doctors
能够治疗他
who can take care of him.
而你们觉得只有你们
And your thinking is that only you guys
才有资格坐在这里
are qualified to sit in this room,
无所事事
doing nothing?
如果你们善心大发  那么请考虑下
If you're motivated by caring, just bear in mind
他是一位认真教学的化学老师
he's a dedicated chemistry teacher
有着漂亮的妻子和仰慕他的学生
with a pretty wife and adoring students,
即将为人父
baby on the way.
他老婆还没怀孕
She's not pregnant.
这有什么关系
Would it make a difference?
我可以代劳啊
'Cause I could knock her up.
-植物神经功能失调  -别说了
- Autonomic dysregulation. - Shut up.
你们几个就不能轻点吗
Could you guys keep it down?
你挺过来了  老兄
You made it, bud.
你在麻醉后加强监护病房
You're in the PACU.
你做了手术
Been in surgery.
麻醉反应刚开始消退
The anesthesia's just wearing off.
我出现了硬膜外血肿吗
Did I have an epidural?
没有吧
No.
我的腿没知觉了
'Cause I can't feel my legs.
奇斯医生
Dr. Chase?
罗伯特
Robert?
是我
Yeah.
我是沃尔特·科菲尔德
I'm Walter Cofield.
我是位神经病学家
I'm a neurologist over at...
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
很好
Good.
你现在能回答几个问题吗
Think you're up for answering a couple questions?
我又没法站起来逃跑
Well, it's not like I can get up and run away.
开个玩笑
Wasn't my best joke.
我笑是因为
I'm smiling because,
在过去十二个小时里
for the last 12 hours,
我一直以为你头发是橘黄色的
I've been picturing you with orange hair.
我染回来了
I dyed it back.
你迁怒于豪斯医生吗
Were you angry with Dr. House?
这是个恶作剧
It was a prank.
家常便饭了
It wasn't uncommon.
我略有耳闻
So I've heard.
但并不是说你不会生气
That doesn't mean you couldn't get angry.
你之后的行为可能就是因为这事儿
Might actually contribute to that reaction.
我能问问这有什么关系吗
May I ask why that matters?
你是要证明我分心了
Are you trying to prove that I was distracted,
我的判断出现了偏差是吗
that my judgment was compromised?
奇斯医生  你认为谁该
Who do you think was at fault
为你的遭遇负责呢
for what happened to you, Dr. Chase?
同样  这有什么关系吗
Again, why does it matter?
你是个聪明人
You're a smart doctor.
你对这儿发生的事比谁都清楚
You know what happened here better than anyone,
而且你和豪斯医生共事的时间
and you've worked with Dr. House
比谁都长
longer than anyone.
我觉得自从受伤开始
And I suspect that you've spent every minute
你也一直在琢磨
since this has happened
谁该为此负责这个问题
trying to answer that very question.
我觉得谁都没错
I don't think it was anyone's fault.
当时我很生气
I was angry,
但是我并没有分心
but I wasn't distracted.
我认为  如果我还有机会
And I think that, if there's any chance
站立行走的话
I'm gonna walk again,
也是因为豪斯医生天才般的医术
it's because Dr. House is a genius.
能感觉到热吗
How about warmth?
能感觉盖着的床单吗
Can you feel the sheets on your skin?
都说了什么都感觉不到
I just said I don't feel anything.
豪斯  你要客观啊
Objectivity, House.
会是创伤后脊髓空洞症吗
What about posttraumatic syringomyelia?
蛛网膜下腔形成的脊髓空洞
Syrinx formed in the subarachnoid space,
阻碍脑脊液的流动
blocking the flow of cerebrospinal fluid.
这意味着这是永久性损伤
That'd mean the damage was permanent.
不对
No.
别考虑神经了
Forget the nerves.
豪斯  如果这是完全瘫痪的话
House, if it's total paralysis,
-他一定是  -不一定
- he must have  - Not necessarily.
考虑一下动脉
Think arteries.
脊柱的血液供应被切断了
Blood flow to his spinal column is cut off.
是根动脉的血栓
It's a clot in the radicular artery.
是可以治疗的
That could be fixable.
准备栓子切除术
Prep a room for an embolectomy.
在造成更大伤害前
Let's get that thing out of there
把血栓取出来
before it does any more damage.
如果不是血栓呢
And if it's not a clot?
那你去问福曼医院的保险是否
Then you can ask Foreman if hospital insurance
能报销残疾人专用车
covers ramp-vans.
已经穿过主动脉
You're through the aorta.
就这里
There.
感觉平面在足背第三跖趾关节上
Sensory level is at L5.
这一定是下降段
It must be the descending branch.
能让我看监视器吗
Can I see the monitor?
停住
Stop there.
注入染色剂
Shoot the dye.
-血栓在这里  -别高兴太早
- There it is. - Don't get too excited.
我们还没取出来呢
We still got to get it out.
还是有可能造成永久性损伤
Still could have done permanent damage.
病人没有患植物神经功能失调
Patient does not have autonomic dysregulation.
他的尿液袋中有血迹
There's blood in his urine bag.
肾脏在衰竭
Kidneys are failing.
-豪斯  现在没空  -就得现在
- House, not now. - Got to be now.
一旦普林斯顿综合医院有床位福曼就要把
Foreman is transferring our guy to Princeton General
病人转到那里去
as soon as there's a bed available.
他号称自打出了刺伤事件这边的医生
Says the doctors here can no longer be objective
无法客观行医了
since the stabbing.
就在这样一个
In the middle of a procedure
事关你性命的手术中
that could basically save your life,
豪斯还想来拉人
House is actually trying to drag people away?
你怎么会和这种人共事
How do you work with a guy like that?
他没有想拉人的意思
He wasn't trying to pull anybody away.
他们已经拒绝参与那个病例了
Everyone had already refused to work on that case.
他心知肚明
He knew the answer.
他是想来看看我
He wanted to check on me.
但他要找个借口
But he needed an excuse.
否则别人会说他关心我
Otherwise, he could be accused of caring.
这么说你的证词是
So your testimony is that
正是豪斯医生的这种完全漠视的态度
Dr. House's complete lack of concern
体现出他深沉的关心
is evidence of his deep concern?
刚才是你动了下吗
Did you just do that?
什么
What?
你动下脚趾
Wiggle your toes.
你感觉到了吗
Do you feel that?
恭喜你
Congratulations.
确实是血栓引起的
It was the clot.
造成短时间动脉闭塞
Short occlusion time of the artery,
等肿胀消退后  你应该...
when the swelling goes down, you should...
至少能恢复一部分腿部功能
gain back at least some of the function.
对不起  还有件事
One more thing. Sorry.
你知道把手术刀
You knew that your patient was at risk
放在病人可触及的地方
for a psychotic break
他会有精神崩溃的危险
when you brought a scalpel within his reach.
为什么无视这个风险
Why did you ignore that risk?
我觉得就皮疹的想法我是对的
I thought I was right about the rash.
若回到当时  我还会那么做
I would do it again.
同感
I thought so.
就这么一句"同感"吗
What, that's it? "I thought so"?
你到底什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
你肆无忌惮的公然藐视你的上司
You brazenly defied your boss.
现在的问题是
Now that happened
要么是豪斯医生自认为那没有关系
either because Dr. House has established that that's okay in his world,
要么是他的恶作剧让你分心了
or his prank war distracted you,
亦或是豪斯把用药当做游戏
or House makes medicine a game,
而你只是想打败他
and you just wanted to beat him.
不管怎样
Whatever the reason,
你都可能再也无法行走
it boils down to the fact that you may never walk again
全是因为豪斯营造了让你们鲁莽行事的氛围
because House created an atmosphere that promotes recklessness.
这是最后一轮讯问
This will be our last round of questions.
我已经和奇斯医生谈过了
I've spoken with Dr. Chase.
知道吧  他已经能动了
You know he regained movement.
不知道
No.
对于奇斯医生受伤的事
Are you really this indifferent
你真的无动于衷吗
to the fact that Dr. Chase is hurt?
你停止录音是因为谈话与案件无关
We're going off the record because this is irrelevant,
还是你想打我呢
or are you gonna hit me?
你为什么不去道歉
Why don't you go tell the guy you're sorry--
我没有错
I didn't do anything wrong.
这不是认罪
It's not an admission of guilt.
他是你的朋友  而且情况很不好
He's your friend, and he's not well.
他只是我的同事
He's a coworker.
是一个你认识了十年
Coworker whom you've known for almost ten years
差点见了阎王
who nearly died
至今仍在担心是否能再次走路的同事
and who's still scared he may not walk.
你会因为我态度恶劣解雇我吗
Are you going to have me fired for bad manners?
只是试图了解你
Just trying to understand you.
为什么像你这样身在要位
Why a man in your position,
才华横溢
with your abilities,
却总是做混蛋事呢
is incapable of shaking the impulse to act like an ass.
能不能恢复录音走完这个过场啊
Could we go back on the record and get this over with?
把维柯丁收起来  豪斯医生
Put the Vicodin away, Dr. House.
我腿疼
My leg hurts.
有意思吗
Is that supposed to be funny?
两起爆炸
Two explosions.
还没结束呢
We're not done here.
等等
Hey, hold on.
关门
Close it up.
把他抬出来
Take him out of there.
福曼医生知道你会这样
Dr. Foreman said you'd try this.
所以让我转告你这已经不是你的病人了
Said to tell you he's no longer your patient.
出发
Let's go!
等等
Wait.
我得去取车
I have to get to my car.
你丈夫的淋巴有肿瘤
Your husband has a tumor in his lymph nodes.
你之前的诊断都是错的
You've been wrong every time.
好吧  这次肯定错不了
Yeah, well, not this time.
教室里的爆炸
The explosion in the classroom
导致癌细胞扩散
caused the cancer cells to break open.
也就是肿瘤溶解综合症
It's called tumor lysis syndrome.
他体内的电解质失调
His body's flooded with an excess of phosphates,
磷酸盐 钾离子和酸浓度不正常
potassium, acids,
都是癌症的诱因
all kinds of cancerous junk.
所以导致了瘫痪  流血
It explains the paralysis, the bleeding,
心脏  肾以及其他一切问题
the heart and kidney issues, everything.
那他为什么会精神崩溃
What about the psychotic break?
是我们的原因
Turns out we caused that.
他还能治
This is treatable. Okay?
告诉新医生
You have to tell the new doctors
给他做全身放疗和血浆置换术
that he needs total body radiation and plasmapheresis.
请把拐杖拿开
Move your cane, please.
科菲尔德在哪里
Where's Cofield?
他说你走了
He said you walked out.
好吧  我又回来了  继续做声明
Well, I'm walking back. I'm not done testifying.
显然已经结束了
Apparently you were.
他说明天做决定
Said he'd have his decision tomorrow.
这次案子很棘手
This case is a fiasco.
我一夜未眠
Didn't sleep last night.
显然  豪斯医生才华横溢
Dr. House is obviously brilliant...
众所周知
Well, I think we've heard enough.
但是豪斯医生也很棘手
But Dr. House is also a fiasco.
如果我让他免责
If I were to exonerate him,
宽恕他的幼稚鲁莽
condone his completely reckless, immature,
甚至于厌世的习惯
almost misanthropic behavior,
那就意味着
I would essentially be sending a message
告诉医院里的所有医生
to all the other doctors in this hospital
他的这种行为是被允许的
that it's okay to act that way and--
抱歉
Sorry.
我们还没说完
We're in the middle of something.
我知道
I know.
我是来找豪斯医生的
I came to speak with Dr. House.
他们告诉我他在这里
And when they told me he was in here,
我觉得有责任告诉大家
I thought I should say something.
我是说
I mean...
他并不是我所见过的医生中人最好的
He wasn't the nicest doctor I've ever met.
这也是众所周知的
Well, I think we've heard enough.
但他是对的
But he was right.
他们发现肿瘤了
They found the tumor.
他们在进行血浆置换术清除肿瘤细胞
They are removing it, and they are starting plasmapheresis.
据说应该能痊愈
They expect a full recovery.
他救了我丈夫的命
He saved my husband's life.
说完了
I guess that's it.
再次感谢
Thanks again.
正如我所说
As I was saying,
豪斯医生的治疗过程是危险不当的
Dr. House's process is dangerous, inappropriate.
但是结果是有效的
But he is effective.
我认为若改变那个治疗过程
I've decided that I would be doing this hospital
无疑将会对医院带来损失
a disservice if I did anything to change that process.
恭喜你  豪斯医生
Congratulations, Dr. House.
无人需对此次事件负责
This unfortunate stabbing incident is officially nobody's fault.
懦夫
Coward.
什么
Excuse me?
你记了20页纸的笔记
You've got, like, 20 pages of notes there.
你至少得折腾我们半小时吧
You were expecting to bore us for at least half an hour.
这是我的假释表
You got my parole form in here.
你本来打算送我回监狱
You were gonna send me back to prison.
豪斯  别说了
House, stop.
好事常有
Good things usually happen;
坏事不常有
bad things sometimes happen.
那个差点做了寡妇的女人
The fact that that would-be widow
及时进来感化了你那软弱感伤的心
came in just in time to sob all over your soft, mushy heart
而且他的丈夫也被救活了
and the fact that her husband's gonna live
这都与我是否做错无关
does not change whether or not I did the right thing.
你是怎么瞒过我
How'd you get the firing wire
把火线装进维柯丁的瓶子里的
into the Vicodin bottle without me noticing?
我有理由这么做吗
Why'd I even have to?
橙色的头发是怎么回事
What was the point of the orange hair?
你头发的味道和亚当斯一样
Your hair smelled like Adams.
但你不可能瞒过我和她在一起
And since there's no way that you're doing her without me knowing,
那就是你只是用了她的洗发水
it means you were just doing her shampoo.
说明你是和某个新认识的女孩出去喝酒到天明
Which means you were out late drinking with some new girl
或者压根没新女孩
or because there is no new girl.
你为了省时在医院洗澡
You were trying to make up time by showering at the hospital
因为你懒得买洗发水
because you're too lazy to buy your own shampoo.
所以我找到个方式通知你别迟到
So I found a way to let you know to not be late.
为什么不直接告诉我
You couldn't just ask me to stop being late?
那有什么意思
What fun would that be?
这不好玩
None of this is fun, House.
他们认为你被刺
They decided that your being stabbed...
无人需要负责
Was nobody's fault.
他们错了
They're wrong.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
还有事吗
Anything else?
我很忙
I'm kind of busy.
没了
No. That was it.
准备好了
I've got it.